Hi~~
大家好~~
Friends
今天我们来聊聊
the confrontation between the Federal Reserve and the White House.
美联储和白宫之间的对抗。
You can see Trump
你可以看到，特朗普
throws out a heavy policy every few days
每隔几天就会推出一项重大政策
to shock the market.
来冲击市场。
But I feel that
但我认为
the contradiction between him and the Federal Reserve
他与美联储之间的矛盾
is a huge risk that is seriously underestimated by the market.
是一个巨大的风险，而市场严重低估了这一风险。
If it is not handled well,
如果处理不当，
it might not just be a black swan event.
这可能不仅仅是一起黑天鹅事件。
It is very likely to become a
它极有可能成为一颗
financial nuclear bomb.
金融核弹。
Let's relax a bit
让我们放松一下，
take a look at the verbal battle between Trump and Powell.
来看看特朗普和鲍威尔之间的口水战。
Let's be honest.
说实话吧。
Trump 's ability to speak trash is really beyond words.
特朗普的垃圾话能力真是令人叹为观止。
He has been bashing Powell for several months
他几个月来一直在抨击鲍威尔，而且
without repeating himself.
没有重复说过同样的话。
From the first day of taking office, he blasted the Federal Reserve
从上任第一天起，他就猛烈抨击美联储，
and said that they should cut interest rates immediately.
并表示他们应该立即降低利率。
He repeatedly accused Powell of acting too late and too slowly.
他多次指责鲍威尔行动太迟、太慢。
Look at Europe,
看看欧洲，
which started to cut interest rates early
它很早就开始降息，
and has cut interest rates 7 times in a row.
并且已经连续降息7次。
Why is it that you, a "stubborn old man", cut the rate halfway and stop?
为什么你这个“固执的老头”会把价格降低一半然后就停工呢？
Of course, I added "stubborn old man" for him.
当然，我还给他加了个“固执的老头”的标签。
On Powell's side, he
鲍威尔
always said slowly that
一直慢慢地说，
we need to rely on data,
我们需要依靠数据，
we need Data Dependent
我们需要数据依赖，
We have to maintain the independence of the Federal Reserve and
我们必须维护美联储的独立性，
But in April
但到了四月份，
Trump
特朗普
seemed to have entered a violent mode.
似乎进入了一种激烈的模式。
if the Federal Reserve did not cut interest
如果美联储不降息，
the United States would be finished
美国就完了。
The sooner Powell leaves, the better.
鲍威尔越早下台越好。
If I want him to leave,
如果我想让他离开，
he won't stay for long
他不会待太久。这
Meaning that
意味着
he wants to fire Powell, the chairman of the Federal Reserve
他想解雇美联储主席鲍威尔。
Powell responded that day and said that
鲍威尔当天回应说，
the US president has no right to fire me
美国总统无权解雇他。正当人们
When you thought the war was escalating,
以为战争升级时，
the next day Trump softened again
第二天特朗普的态度再次软化，
and said that he didn't plan to remove Powell from his position.
表示他并不打算解除鲍威尔的职务。
I was just saying
我只是说
you heard it wrong.
你听错了。
But he started to nickname Powell
但他开始给鲍威尔起绰号，
and called him
叫他
"Too Tate Powell".
“太泰特·鲍威尔”。
"Mr. Too Late",
“迟到先生”，
you are a fool
你真是个傻瓜，其实你和
as well as I do.
我一样什么都不懂。
In fact, the conflict between the two sides
事实上，双方的冲突
is that Trump wants Powell
在于，特朗普希望鲍威尔
to cut interest rates as soon as possible
尽快降息，但鲍威尔却
No way!
不肯！ 就这样
That's all.
。
The logic behind it
其背后的逻辑
is not difficult to understand.
并不难理解。
We analysed
我们
the US government in the last video.
在上一期视频中分析了美国政府。
Although it has so many goals
虽然它有很多目标，但目前
the most important
最重要
and core one
和最核心的目标
is to ease fiscal pressure
是缓解财政压力，
and the top priority
而首要任务
is to reduce the government's borrowing costs
是降低政府的借贷成本，
that is, to lower interest rates.
也就是降低利率。
At the same time, he also has a major goal
与此同时，他还有一个主要目标，
which is to hope that the dollar will depreciate
那就是希望美元贬值，
to ease the pressure of manufacturing outflows.
以缓解制造业资金外流的压力。
You see, these two major goals
你看，这两个主要目标都
require lowering interest rates
需要降低利率。
This is the main appeal of the White House.
这就是白宫的主要诉求。
In order to get Powell to cooperate
为了让鲍威尔合作，
Trump plays the bad guy and
特朗普扮演坏人，而
Treasury Secretary Bessent plays the good guy.
财政部长贝森特扮演好人。
He goes to breakfast with Powell every week
他每周都和鲍威尔一起吃早餐，试图
to persuade him.
说服他。
The core goal of the Federal Reserve
美联储的核心目标
is to control inflation.
是控制通货膨胀。
In the past year,
过去一年，
the inflation in the United States has actually been controlled below 3%.
美国的通货膨胀率实际上被控制在了3%以下。
So you see,
你看，
the Federal Reserve has already cut interest rates by 100 basis points last year.
美联储去年已经降息100个基点了。
However, this year,
然而，今年
because Trump's policy uncertainty is too high
由于特朗普的政策不确定性过高，
especially Tariffs
尤其是关税问题，
may also trigger a resurgence of inflation,
可能会引发通胀反弹，
so Powell suspended interest rate cuts this year
因此鲍威尔暂停了今年的降息计划，
and said, "I have to wait and see,
并表示：“我必须拭目以待，
I have to see clear data to prove that
我必须看到明确的数据来证明
prices have indeed cooled down, and then
物价确实已经降温，然后
I will cut interest rates."
我才会降息。”
It can even be said that the demands of both sides
甚至可以说，双方的要求
are simple, clear and conflicting,
简单、明确且相互矛盾，
which led to Trump's crazy attack against Powell
这导致了特朗普对鲍威尔的疯狂攻击。
Let's use this incident
让我们借此事件
to talk about the relationship between
谈谈
the Federal Reserve and the US government
美联储与美国政府、
the Treasury Department and the White House
财政部与白宫之间的关系。
Don't think that Trump is a special case.
不要以为特朗普是个特例。
In fact, the relationship between
事实上，作为
the Federal Reserve, the most important central bank in the world,
世界上最重要的中央银行的美联储
and the successive presidents of the United States
与
who can be said to be one of the most powerful people in the world,
可以说是世界上最有权势的人之一的美国历任总统之间的关系，
has always been very subtle.
一直非常微妙。
They are not simply independent of each other
他们并非彼此独立，
nor are they in collusion and wearing the same pants.
也并非串通一气、步调一致。
In order to deeply understand
为了深入了解
the love-hate relationship between the Federal Reserve and the White House
美联储与白宫之间爱恨交织的关系，
and understand the logic here,
并理解其中的逻辑，
I think the best way
我认为最好的方法
is to take everyone to quickly look at
是带领大家快速回顾
the eight major battles that the Federal Reserve has experienced
美联储在过去一个世纪经历的八场重大战役
in the past century,
，也就是
his own "War of Independence",
他自己的“独立战争”，
and then we will analyse
然后我们将分析
how Trump might deal with Powell.
特朗普可能会如何对待鲍威尔。
I tell you, it's very interesting.
我跟你说，这很有意思。
Let's begin.
我们开始吧。
1913, the U.S. Congress passed the Federal Reserve Act.
1913年，美国国会通过了《联邦储备法》。 由
of 12 reserve banks,
12家储备银行组成的中央银行——
the Federal Reserve, was established
联邦储备系统——成立了。
The law stipulates that it is "independent but supervised"
法律规定它是“独立但受监督的”。
It can independently implement monetary policy
它可以独立实施货币政策，
but at this time
但当时
its independence was only theoretical
它的独立性仅仅停留在理论层面。
The early monetary policy
早期的货币政策
basically had to cooperate with the needs of department of treasury
基本上必须与财政部的需求相配合。
Generally speaking,
总的来说，
if the full score of independence is 10,
如果独立性满分是10分，
I would give it 5 points
我会给它5分，
It still fail
它仍然不及格。
Soon the Federal Reserve ushered in its first battle,
不久之后，联邦储备系统就迎来了它的第一场战役，
which was the gold war in the 1930s.
那就是20世纪30年代的黄金战争。 美国
When the Federal Reserve was first established,
联邦储备系统成​​立之初，
the United States implemented the gold standard.
美国实行的是金本位制。
The law required that for every dollar issued, you
法律规定，每发行一美元，就
must have 40% gold as support.
必须有 40% 的黄金作为支撑。
So the Federal Reserve
所以，美联储
is actually a bit like an ultimate gold merchant.
实际上有点像一个终极黄金商人。
How much gold you have
你拥有多少黄金，就
is equivalent to how much money you print.
相当于你印了多少钱。
Although the gold standard sounds very reasonable
虽然金本位制听起来非常合理，
and strictly limits the issuance of currency
并且严格限制了货币发行，但
there is actually a very serious problem here.
实际上这里存在一个非常严重的问题。
The problem is that it forces the Fed
问题在于，这迫使美联储
to tighten its monetary policy when the economy is in a recession,
在经济衰退时收紧货币政策，从而
which intensifies the magnitude of economic shocks.
加剧了经济冲击的程度。
When the Great Depression broke out in 1929,
1929年大萧条爆发时，
people kept looking for banks to exchange their gold.
人们不断寻找银行兑换黄金。
The Fed's gold reserves
美联储的黄金储备
plummeted from $4.5 billion to $3.2 billion,
从 45 亿美元骤降至 32 亿美元，
which greatly limited its ability to issue currency.
这极大地限制了其发行货币的能力。
At the height of the crisis when stimulus policies were most needed,
在危机最严重、最需要刺激政策的时候，
the Fed was restricted and had
美联储受到限制，
to tighten its monetary policy .
不得不收紧货币政策。
So at the White House
因此，在白宫，
President Roosevelt took the lead and
罗斯福总统率先
promulgated the Gold Reserve Act in 1934.
于 1934 年颁布了《黄金储备法》。
After the gold standard was abandoned,
金本位制被废除后，
the dollar was no longer backed by gold.
美元不再与黄金挂钩。
At the same time gold was nationalised and
与此同时，黄金被收归国有，
all citizens had to hand in their gold.
所有公民都必须上交自己的黄金。
The key point was that the object of his handing in gold was not the Federal Reserve
关键在于，他上交黄金的对象不是美联储，
but the U.S. Treasury Department.
而是美国财政部。
He also required the Federal Reserve to give the vast majority of its gold
他还要求美联储将其绝大部分黄金移交
to the Treasury Department.
给财政部。
Once this move was made,
这一举措实施后，
on the one hand, the Federal Reserve's functions in gold
一方面，美联储在黄金领域的职能
were almost completely taken back.
几乎完全被收回。
On the other hand,
另一方面，
the Federal Reserve could control the discount rate
美联储可以
in terms of monetary policy.
通过货币政策控制贴现率。
Basically, the Treasury Department had to give
基本上，财政部不得不
priority to meeting the demand for treasury bond issuance, which
优先满足国债发行需求，这
basically completely undermined the Federal Reserve.
基本上完全削弱了美联储的作用。
The then Chairman of the Federal Reserve later recalled and joked
当时的美联储主席后来回忆说，
that although he was nominally the Chairman of the Central Bank,
虽然他名义上是中央银行主席，但
he was actually
实际上他
just an
只是
assistant to the Treasury Department
财政部的一名助理，
doing some very basic administrative work.
从事一些非常基本的行政工作。 此后
Soon after that
不久，
World War II came.
第二次世界大战爆发了。
In order to cope with the war,
为了应对战争，
the Federal Reserve lost even its superficial independence.
美联储甚至失去了表面上的独立性。
The Treasury Department basically forced him
财政部实际上强迫他
to sign an agreement
签署了一项协议，
requiring the Federal Reserve to purchase Treasury bonds at a very low interest rate
要求美联储以低于 2.5% 的极低利率购买国债，
to help the Treasury Department raise funds.
以帮助财政部筹集资金。
So you see, during this period,
所以你看，在此期间，
although the Federal Reserve
虽然美联储
was still an independent central bank in name
名义上仍然是一个独立的中央银行，但
it was actually
实际上它是
a subsidiary of the Treasury Department.
财政部的子公司。
The Fed lost the gold war and
美联储输掉了黄金战争，
its independence score was 2 points.
其独立性得分仅为 2 分。
Originally, after World War II,
二战结束后，
the Fed should have been more independent
美联储本应更加独立
and stopped backing up the Treasury Department
，停止支持财政部。
However, the US government was about to start the Korean War,
然而，当时美国政府即将发动朝鲜战争，
and the government still needed money.
政府仍然需要资金。
President Truman still wanted
杜鲁门总统仍然希望
to continue the model of the Fed printing money and buying treasury bonds.
继续沿用美联储印钞和购买国债的模式。
Well, this time the Fed stood its ground
这一次，美联储坚持了自己的立场。毕竟，
After all, because it had printed too much money before,
由于之前印钞过多，
the inflation in the United States had exceeded 9%
美国的通货膨胀率已经超过9%。
If it continued like this,
如果这种情况继续下去，
the economy would really be in trouble.
经济真的会陷入困境。
So the Fed said no, no,
所以美联储
and it did not agree to Truman's request.
拒绝了杜鲁门的请求。
After several very difficult negotiations,
经过几次非常艰难的谈判，
the then Secretary of the Treasury,
当时的财政部长（他
who was also a good friend of Truman
也是杜鲁门的好朋友）
used a shady trick.
使用了一种不正当的手段。
He did not communicate with the Fed
他没有与美联储沟通，
but directly gave a public speech in January 1951
而是在 1951 年 1 月直接发表公开演讲，
saying that the Federal Reserve
称美联储
had agreed to the Treasury's treasury bond purchase plan.
已同意财政部的国债购买计划。
When the Chairman of the Federal Reserve heard it, he became anxious and
美联储主席听到这话后，感到焦急，
asked, "When did I agree to it?"
问道：“我什么时候同意过这件事？”
The contradiction between both sides intensified.
双方矛盾加剧。
After all, the Fed is still independent in law
毕竟，美联储在法律上仍然是独立的，
and has some capital to be tough.
而且拥有足够的资金采取强硬措施。
He said that
他说，
if Treasury Department still has such a tough attitude,
如果财政部继续保持这种强硬态度，那么
our policies
我们
will be completely independent in the future,
未来的政策将完全独立自主，
there is no room for negotiation.
没有任何谈判的余地。
After a month of fierce public conflict,
经过一个月的激烈公开冲突，
the Treasury finally
财政部最终
gave in.
让步。
The Fed and the Treasury
美联储和财政部
signed the famous 1951 Monetary Agreement.
签署了著名的1951年货币协议。
The Treasury agreed that
财政部同意
the Fed would no longer purchase Treasury bonds at a fixed interest rate
美联储不再以固定利率购买国债。
The market generally believed that
市场普遍认为，
the real independence of the modern Federal Reserve
现代美联储的真正独立性
began with this 1951 agreement.
始于1951年的这项协议。
The Fed won the independence battle
美联储
with an independence score of 6 points.
以 6 分的独立性得分赢得了这场独立性之战。
As the price of the negotiation,
作为谈判的代价，
the chairman of the Fed resigned.
美联储主席辞职了。
He was replaced by
他被
the Treasury who was in charge of negotiations at the time
当时负责谈判的财政部助理部长取代，
His name was William Martin.
他的名字叫威廉·马丁。
Remember this name, it's very important.
记住这个名字，它非常重要。
You see,
你看，
the Treasury had a good idea.
财政部有个好主意。
I would place one of my own in the Federal Reserve
我会在美联储安插一名自己的人，
so that even if I signed the agreement,
这样即使我签署了协议，也
could cooperate on policy.
能在政策方面进行合作。
But they didn't expect that
但他们没想到，他们安插在美联储的
the so-called "one of their own"
所谓“自己人”竟然
would become the founder of the Federal Reserve's independence
会成为美联储独立的奠基人，
and served nearly 20 years
并担任美联储主席近 20 年，
and is the longest-serving chairman in history.
是历史上任期最长的美联储主席。
A building of the Federal Reserve
美联储的一栋大楼以
is named after him.
他的名字命名。
Let me talk a little about
让我简单谈谈
William Martin .
威廉·马丁。
Just looking at his resume, you can tell
光看他的简历就知道
that he must be very smart.
他一定非常聪明。
He graduated from Yale University.
他毕业于耶鲁大学。
His first job
他毕业后的第一份工作
after graduation was in a brokerage firm.
是在一家经纪公司。
He became a partner in the company after two years.
两年后，他成为了公司的合伙人。
At the age of 29, he became a member of the board of directors of the New York Stock Exchange.
29岁时，他成为纽约证券交易所董事会成员。
At the age of 31, he became the president of the New York Stock Exchange.
31岁时，他成为纽约证券交易所总裁。
He was called the "Wall Street Prodigy".
他被称为“华尔街神童”。
During World War II
二战期间
he joined the army and became a colonel.
他参军，并晋升为上校。
After World War II, he joined the Treasury
二战后，他加入财政部，
and became an assistant secretary of the Treasury.
并成为财政部助理部长。
Then he became the chairman of the Fed
后来他成为美联储主席
and served fo 19 years
，任职长达19年。真是
Incredible isn't it
不可思议，不是吗？
I feel that his 19 years in office
我觉得他19年的任期
on the policy logic of the Federal Reserve
对美联储的政策逻辑
and the game relationship between it and the Treasury Department.
以及美联储与财政部之间的关系产生了深远的影响。
With the legal protection of the previously signed agreement,
在之前签署的协议的法律保护下，
Martin's attitude
马丁的态度
is obviously much tougher than that of previous Federal Reserve chairmen.
显然比以往的美联储主席要强硬得多。
In most cases,
在大多数情况下，
price control
价格管制
is still the most important consideration.
仍然是最重要的考虑因素。
From 1952 to 1965,
从 1952 年到 1965 年，
the average inflation rate in the United States was only 1.3%
美国的平均通货膨胀率仅为 1.3%，
which is known as the "Martin Miracle".
这被称为“马丁奇迹”。
In 1965, the United States was mired in the Vietnam War
1965年，美国深陷越南战争泥潭，
and its finances were tight.
财政状况十分紧张。
At that time, President Johnson began to put pressure on Martin
当时，约翰逊总统开始向马丁施压，要求其
to ease the currency.
放松货币政策。
Martin said,
马丁说：
"I will not cut interest rates"
“我不会降低利率。​​”
Not only will I not cut it
我不仅不会降低利率，
I will raise interest rates by 0.5%.
还会将利率提高0.5%。 难道
Isn't that infuriating?"
不令人愤怒吗？”
President Johnson was really angry at the time
约翰逊总统当时非常生气，
He said, "Our children are dying in Vietnam,
他说：“我们的孩子正在越南死去，
but you are unwilling to print money. "
但你们却不愿意印钞票。”
If Martin
如果马丁生活
were to be in today's world
在今天，
he would definitely be a hawk among hawks.
他绝对会是鹰派中的鹰派。
At that time, the inflation in the United States was actually less than 2%,
当时，美国的通货膨胀率实际上低于2%，
but Martin felt that the unemployment rate was too low
但马丁认为失业率过低，存在经济
and he had the risk of overheating
过热的风险
of the economy, so he still raised the interest rate to 4.5%
，因此他仍然将利率提高到4.5%。
However, this does not mean that Martin
然而，这并不意味着马丁
is a hard-nosed person
是一个
who does not care about the needs of the government.
不顾政府利益的铁腕人物。总而言之，
His style,
他的风格
is that he is tough in principle
是原则强硬，
but intermittently gives in.
但偶尔也会做出让步。
For example, in 1953, Eisenhower put pressure on him
例如，1953年，艾森豪威尔向他施压；
and in the 1960s, Kennedy put pressure on him too
20世纪60年代，肯尼迪也向他施压，
and he actually gave in and
而他最终都做出了让步，
cooperated with the monetary policy of the Treasury.
与财政部的货币政策进行了合作。
In general,
总的来说，
Martin did establish a very good
马丁确实建立了一个非常优秀的
independent Federal Reserve
独立美联储，
but his independence
但他的独立性
did not come entirely from power
并非完全来自权力
or legal protection
或法律保护，
but a lot of it came from his balancing act.
很大程度上来自于他巧妙的平衡策略。
He created a system called group of four
他创建了一个名为“四人小组”的机制，成员
include the chairman of the Fed, the secretary of the Treasury,
包括美联储主席、财政部长、
the White House budget director
白宫预算主任
and the chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers.
和…… 经济顾问委员会。
These four people sit together and have a meal
这四位成员坐在一起用餐
and communicate
交流，
it also helps the Federal Reserve
这也有助于美联储
maintain its relationship with the White House.
维持与白宫的关系。
So you see
所以你看，
Powell's tradition of having dinner with Bessent
鲍威尔与贝森特共进晚餐的传统是
has been passed down from that era,
从
the Martin era.
马丁时代传承下来的。
I also count it as a battle.
我也把它看作是一场战斗，
It can be regarded as a victory for the Federal Reserve.
可以被视为美联储的胜利。
The independence score has risen to 7 points
独立性评分已经上升到7分。
Are you curious about when it will go up again?
你好奇它什么时候会再次上升吗？
By the way,
顺便说一句，
this score
这个评分
is my personal subjective score.
是我个人的主观评分，
It has no authority.
不具有权威性。
If you think it is wrong,
如果你认为它错了，
then you are right
那你就对了。此时
At this point, have you discovered that
，你是否已经发现，
the Federal Reserve and the US government,
美联储和美国政府之间的
have their differences mostly when
分歧主要体现在
the Fed feels that it needs to raise interest rates
美联储认为需要提高利率
and tighten monetary policy
、收紧货币政策，
but the US government will not let it.
而美国政府却不允许的时候？
Economist Hertzl commented that
经济学家赫茨尔评论说，
the Fed Chairman often has to face
美联储主席经常要面对
a president and Congress who are hostile to interest rate hikes.
一位对加息持敌对态度的总统和国会。
Why is he hostile?
为什么他会敌视加息呢？
In fact, as a government,
事实上，作为政府，
there are two main reasons why he does not like to raise interest rates.
他不愿意加息主要有两个原因。
One is that raising interest rates will suppress the economy
一是加息会抑制经济，二是……
and it is a key indicator for everyone to measure
衡量总统政绩的关键指标之一
It is the economic performance during his administration
是其执政期间的经济表现。
Therefore, the period when all previous US presidents
因此，历任美国总统
put the most intense pressure on the Federal Reserve
对美联储施加最大压力的时期
is generally the year before the election year
通常是选举年的前一年，
especially the year before the re-election year.
尤其是连任年的前一年。
Another reason is that
另一个原因是，
the higher the government's debt
政府债务
and interest rate
和利率越高，
the higher the government's borrowing cost.
政府的借贷成本就越高。
Therefore, every time a war needs money,
因此，每当战争需要资金时，
the pressure on the Fed from the Treasury is particularly great.
财政部对美联储的压力就格外巨大。
You see, these two points,
你看，
economic development and debt costs, are
经济发展和债务成本这两点是美国政府
the most core and underlying interests
最核心、最根本的利益所在
of the US government.
。
Therefore, the president and
因此，总统和
the government are sometimes helpless.
政府有时也无能为力。
If you catch up with a very hawkish Fed chairman,
如果遇到一位鹰派极强的美联储主席，
prices are strictly controlled, but
价格虽然会被严格控制，但
the economy may be very bad
经济状况可能在
during the years when you are in office.
你执政期间非常糟糕。
The Fed chairman can still be re-elected
美联储主席仍然可以连任，
and can survive longer than yourself.
而且任期可能比你更长。
In the end, everyone still blames you as the president.
最终，所有人仍然会把责任归咎于你这位总统。
So can you understand why the president is eager
所以，你能理解为什么总统在
to raise interest rates as soon as the Fed raises interest rates?
美联储加息后会急于提高利率吗？他的第一
The reflex is to
反应是
jump up and grumble a few words.
跳出来抱怨几句。
On the other hand, when the interest rate is cut,
另一方面，当利率下调时，
the president is very happy.
总统却非常高兴。
You see, during Trump’s first term,
你看，在特朗普的第一任期内，
Powell raised interest rates four times in a row in 2018.
鲍威尔在2018年连续四次加息。
Trump was outspoken about Powell
特朗普曾公开批评鲍威尔
and the Federal Reserve.
和美联储。
But when the pandemic came,
但当疫情来袭时，
Powell quickly and urgently
鲍威尔迅速而紧急地
cut interest rates to 0
将利率降至0，
and launched quantitative easing
并启动了量化宽松政策。
Trump praised him
特朗普称赞
Powell, you did great
鲍威尔：“你做得太棒了！”
Well, let’s go back to the Martin era.
好，让我们回到马丁时代。
Why is it still Martin?
为什么还要提马丁？
He will be removed soon .
他很快就要下台了。
In 1969, inflation in the United States began to rise rapidly.
1969年，美国的通货膨胀开始迅速上升。
Martin strongly raised interest rates by 1%.
马丁大幅度地将利率提高了1%。
The newly elected President Nixon was furious.
新当选的总统尼克松勃然大怒。
He had just promised American voters
他刚刚
in the election the previous year that he would revitalise the American economy .
在前一年的选举中向美国选民承诺，他将重振美国经济。尼克松一上任就
he met Martin, such a stubborn old man
遇到了马丁这个固执的老头，
and publicly bombarded Martin,
并公开抨击马丁，
saying that you are pushing the economy into recession
说他正在把经济推向衰退。
Meanwhile Martin
而马丁当时已经担任
had been the chairman of the Federal Reserve for nearly 20 years.
美联储主席近20年了。
He stood strong and
他立场坚定，
completely ignored the pressure from Nixon.
完全无视了尼克松的压力。
Nixon wanted to replace Martin quickly,
尼克松想尽快撤换马丁，
but what was the problem?
但问题出在哪里呢？
The US president
美国总统
could not legally
不能随意
dismiss the chairman of the Federal Reserve at will
解雇美联储主席。
Nixon used a shady trick at the time
当时，尼克松耍了个阴招，
because Martin's term was to expire in 1970
因为马丁的任期将于1970
the next year.
年到期。
Although Nixon could not force him to step down directly
虽然尼克松不能直接逼他下台，但
he announced in advance that
他提前宣布
the new chairman of the Federal Reserve was named Arthur Burns,
新任美联储主席是阿瑟·伯恩斯，而伯恩斯
who was also his own man.
也是尼克松的亲信。
In this way, all the attention and
这样一来，市场的所有注意力都
turned to the successor Burns.
转移到了继任者伯恩斯身上。
In fact, it was equivalent to sidelining Martin,
实际上，这相当于排挤马丁，相当于
which was equivalent to forcing Martin to step down in advance.
提前逼迫马丁下台。
Don't you think this is very similar to Powell now?
你不觉得这和现在的鲍威尔很像吗？
Powell's term will also expire next year.
鲍威尔的任期也将在明年到期。
Trump also blasted him crazily
特朗普也曾疯狂抨击他。
That is why many people speculate that
因此，许多人猜测
Trump will use Nixon's trick
特朗普会效仿尼克松，
of announcing Powell's successor in advance to sideline him.
提前宣布鲍威尔的继任者，以此排挤他。
And the policy style of Burns
而
after being recommended by Nixon,
由尼克松推荐上任的伯恩斯，其政策风格
can be summarised in 4 words: Obedience in every way
可以用四个字概括：绝对服从。
He cut the rate as soon as he took office
他上任伊始就降低了利率
and helped Nixon to get re-elected
，帮助尼克松连任，
and then another rate cut.
之后又再次降息。
Moreover, it was not Nixon who put
而且，在很多情况下，并非尼克松
pressure on him
向他施压
in many cases, Burns cut interest rates very actively
，而是伯恩斯主动降低了利率。
How do I know this?
我怎么知道的？
Because the famous Watergate scandal happened later,
因为后来发生了著名的水门事件，
and the White House recordings
白宫的录音
happened to expose some
曝光了
conversations between Nixon and Burns
尼克松和伯恩斯之间的一些对话。
For example, on December 10, 1971,
例如，1971年12月10日，
Burns called Nixon and said, "
伯恩斯打电话给尼克松说：“
Mr. President,
总统先生，
I want to let you know that
我想通知您，
I have lowered the discount rate
我已经将贴现率降至
to 4.5%.
4.5%。”
Nixon was very satisfied
尼克松非常满意，连声
and said
说道：
"Good, Good, Good" .
“好，好，好”。
Another time,
另一次，
Burns said, "In my opinion,
伯恩斯说：“依我之见，
I have done my best to help you become president
我已经尽全力帮助你当选总统，
and establish your reputation and status in American history.
并在美国历史上树立你的声誉和地位。
Look at how
看看我多么
cooperative
配合，在
without you even opening your mouth.
你开口之前就让你满意了。”
Well, I’m half-joking, of course
当然，我这话半开玩笑，
I feel that Burns is like a bootlicker.
我觉得伯恩斯就像个马屁精。
In fact,
事实上，
he is also an
他也是一位
economist with very high academic achievements.
学术成就极高的经济学家。
He also dealt with Nixon,
他也曾与尼克松打交道，
but the intensity was not enough.
但力度不够。
Judging from the results,
从结果来看，
during the Burns period
可以说伯恩斯时期的美联储已经失去了独立性，
The independence score is 3 points.
独立性得分只有3分。
However, as the saying goes, everything will turn around when it reaches
然而，正如俗话所说，凡事皆有两面性，不破不成
its extreme .
。
The Burns period also brought some benefits
伯恩斯时期也带来了一些好处。
It was because he was
正因为他是一位
such a bad chairman
如此糟糕的主席，
that Congress
国会才
began to strictly review the policies of the Federal Reserve
开始严格审查美联储的政策，
and could not let him mess around,
不能让他胡作非为，
especially not under the instruction of the president.
尤其是在总统的指示下。国会
It was clearly stipulated that
明确规定，美联储的
the dual goals are prices and employment
双重目标是控制物价和就业。
The Fed Chairman is required to
美联储主席必须
"Monetary Policy Report" to Congress every six months
每六个月向国会提交一份“货币政策报告”。
and also to attend a hearing of the two houses.
而且我还参加了两院的听证会。
I tell you,
我跟你说，
it was at that hearing that
正是在那次听证会上，
I felt that the Federal Reserve Chairman was pitiful.
我才觉得美联储主席很可怜。
Although he was the chairman
虽然他是主席，但
he sat in the middle of Congress for two hours
他却在国会里坐了两个小时，
and felt like a prisoner.
感觉自己像个囚犯。他
had to be interrogated repeatedly, asking
不得不被反复盘问，问他
why did you raise interest rates and
为什么要提高利率，
why inflation was so high.
为什么通货膨胀这么高，
Why are you printing money?
为什么要印钞票
Why this, why that ,
，为什么这样那样，
a hundred thousand whys
一连串的“为什么”。
And it's like this every year,
而且每年都要这样，
twice.
两次。
When I first started watching, I was really scared by this .
我一开始看的时候，真的被吓到了。
I felt that if I sat there,
我觉得如果我坐在那里，
I would definitely cry.
肯定会哭出来。
Oh, let's get back
哦，我们还是回到
to the topic.
正题吧。
Anyway, after the Burns period,
总之，在伯恩斯时期之后，
Congress greatly strengthened its scrutiny of the Fed
国会大大加强了对美联储的制度
at the institutional level.
性审查。
And then the highlight moment of the Federal Reserve came
然后，美联储迎来了它的高光时刻——
Its next chairman, Paul Walker,
下一任主席保罗·沃克，
you see this highlight moment.
你看看这个高光时刻。
First of all, he is very tall,
首先，他个子很高，
more than two meters tall.
超过两米。
Even inflation will have to bow down
就连通货膨胀都得向他低头。
When Paul Walker came to power in 1979,
保罗·沃克1979年上任时，
he was facing
他面临的
may well be the worst period for the U.S. economy
很可能是美国经济最糟糕的时期。
in nearly a hundred years
近百年来，美国
with an inflation rate of 14%,
通货膨胀率高达14%，
an unemployment rate of 7.5%
失业率高达7.5%，
and out-of-control gold prices,
金价也失控上涨，
the U.S. economy fell into stagflation.
经济陷入滞胀。
After Walker came to power, his extremely tough
沃克上台后，他极其艰巨的
goal was to maintain prices
目标是维持物价稳定，
and suppress inflation.
抑制通货膨胀。
The federal funds rate rose from 11% to more than 20%.
联邦基金利率从11%飙升至20%以上。
After that, inflation was instantly suppressed
此后，通货膨胀率迅速
from 13.5% in 1980
从1980年的13.5%
to 3.2% in 1983.
降至1983年的3.2%，
It was called the "Walker miracle".
被誉为“沃克奇迹”。（此处为笔者
I added it myself .
自加）但
I tell you,
我要说，
don't think that his interest rate hike
别以为他加息就
was that simple
这么简单。
He was under tremendous pressure at the time.
当时他承受着巨大的压力。1982年，
Raising the interest rate to 20%
将利率提高到20%
plunged the U.S. into the worst economic downturn
使美国陷入二战以来最严重的经济衰退
in 1982, the unemployment rate soared to 10.8%.
，失业率飙升至10.8%。
Some small and medium-sized enterprises and farmers went bankrupt on a large scale.
许多中小企业和农场大规模破产。
He often received death threats.
他经常收到死亡威胁。
President Carter privately complained that
卡特总统私下抱怨说，
President Reagan tried to intervene
里根总统试图干预，
but it was useless
但却无济于事。
Walker said that he had to do it his way.
沃克无能为力，声称他必须按自己的方式来。
He even directly rejected the invitation of the White House
他甚至直接拒绝了白宫的邀请，
and said that the Federal Reserve did not serve any political party.
并表示美联储不为任何政党服务。
This period
可以说，这一时期是
the most intense period of conflict between the Fed and the US government
美联储与美国政府冲突最为激烈的时期。
However, time has proved that
然而，时间证明
Walker's choice was right,
沃克的选择是正确的，
but very right.
而且是非常正确的。
After a brief period of pain, the US economy
经过短暂的阵痛，美国经济
regained its vitality for at least 20 years.
至少在20年内恢复了活力。
At that time
当时，
the United States had just left the Bretton Woods system.
美国刚刚脱离布雷顿森林体系。
Walker's strong approach to maintaining dollar inflation
沃克强硬地维持美元通胀，
strengthened the market's confidence in the dollar
增强了市场对美元的信心，
can be said to have laid the foundation for
可以说为
the dollar's position
美元
as the global reserve currency
成为全球储备货币奠定了基础。
It was after Walker that
沃克之后，
although the Fed had a dual mission
尽管美联储肩负着双重使命，
but when the two conflicted,
但当两者发生冲突时，
inflation usually took the lead.
通胀往往占据主导地位。
I gave the Fed's independence score of 9 points
我给沃克时期美联储的独立性打了9分。
Walker's successor, Greenspan,
沃克的继任者格林斯潘
served as the chairman of the Fed for 18 and a half years,
担任美联储主席长达18年半，
which was also the second longest (term).
也是任期第二长的。
If I use one term to summarise his tenure,
如果我用一个任期来衡量…… 总结他的任期，可以用
it is "equivocate".
“模棱两可”来形容。
Greenspan
格林斯潘
is simply a master of language.
简直就是个语言大师，
He has brought the art of language to the extreme.
他把语言艺术发挥到了极致。他的话
It is very ambiguous and
非常含糊，
you can understand it in any way.
你可以用任何方式理解。
For example, he often says, "
例如，他经常说：“
If you think you understand what I say,
如果你认为你理解了我的意思，
then you must have misunderstood what I mean ."
那你一定是误解了我的意思。”这
What on earth do you mean?
到底是什么意思？
He likes to use metaphors.
他喜欢用比喻。
For example, he said that the market is irrationally prosperous.
例如，他说市场非理性地繁荣。
So is it prosperous or overheated?
那么，它是繁荣还是过热呢？在
he went to the congressional hearing to
国会听证会上
answer questions.
回答问题时，他什么也没说。
He insisted that whatever you say about him is reasonable.
他坚持说，无论你对他说什么，都是合理的。
I feel that he has mastered some oriental language arts.
我觉得他掌握了一些东方语言艺术。
But Greenspan
但格林斯潘
actually
实际上
balanced the needs of the market and the Treasury very well.
很好地平衡了市场和财政部的需求。美联储也正是
It was also from him that
从他那里
the Fed emphasised full communication
强调了充分沟通
and synchronisation of market expectations.
和市场预期同步的重要性。
As a veteran who served four presidents,
作为一位服务过四位总统的资深人士，
his prestige during his tenure
他在任期间的声望
can be said to have reached the peak of all Federal Reserve chairmen.
可以说达到了历任美联储主席的巅峰。
In the end, the US president didn't even dare to complain.
最后， 美国总统甚至不敢抱怨。
The independence score is 8 points.
独立性得分8分。
Of course, Greenspan has prestige
当然，格林斯潘声望很高，
and he has maintained the independence of the Fed.
也一直维护着美联储的独立性。
It doesn't mean that he has never made mistakes.
但这并不意味着他从未犯过错。
His excessive relaxation of regulation on financial derivatives
他对金融衍生品监管的过度放松
can be said to be one of the most important reasons
可以说是
that led to the 2008 subprime mortgage crisis.
导致2008年次贷危机的最重要原因之一。
Did you find a pattern?
你看出其中的规律了吗？
The job of the Fed chairman
美联储主席的职责
is not just to control inflation.
不仅仅是控制通胀。
He is essentially
他本质上是
the market and the US government.
市场和美国政府之间的中间人。
He can influence the market
他可以影响市场
and the government
，政府也
can influence the Fed.
可以影响美联储。
The Fed is in the middle and
美联储处于中间位置，
it is not enough to
仅仅坚定地站在市场一边是不够的。
If that were the case, the White House would definitely find a way to deal with you.
如果真是那样，白宫肯定会找到办法对付你。
If it leans towards the government
如果美联储偏向政府，情况
it would be even more serious.
会更加严重。
The market might in turn hit the dollar
市场可能会反过来打压美元，
and deal with both the Fed and the US government.
同时对美联储和美国政府都造成影响。
So the Fed
因此，美联储
actually has
实际上必须在
to seek a very delicate balance in the middle
两者之间寻求一种非常微妙的平衡：
maintaining independence
保持独立性可以
wins the trust of the market, but
赢得市场的信任，但也
you can't offend the government
不能得罪政府
or make the president too unhappy.
或让总统感到不安。 不开心。
Why can Martin and Greenspan
为什么马丁和格林斯潘能
do it for so long?
坚持这么久？
It's not because they are simply tough,
这并非仅仅因为他们强硬，
but because they pay great attention to balance
而是因为他们非常注重平衡，
and are
并且
very good at maneuvering .
善于周旋。
You see, Martin's
你看，马丁的
style is tough in principle
风格原则上强硬，
and intermittently give in
但偶尔也会做出让步，
while Greenpan is a smooth talker
而格林斯潘则是一位能言善辩的人。
They are both very flexible and
他们都非常灵活，并且
stick to independence.
坚持独立性。
They also know how to be tactful .
他们也懂得如何巧妙地处理问题。
So every time there is a change of government,
因此，每次政府更迭，
although the president can appoint a new one
尽管总统可以任命新的主席，但
they'll feel that the chairman is just a bit stubborn
人们会觉得这位主席只是有点固执，
but can still cooperate when he should,
但该合作的时候还是会合作的，
and the market still trusts him.
市场也仍然信任他。
Maybe let's just leave it as is
也许就维持现状吧。
Then the financial crisis era
然后，金融危机时期
saw the arrival of two Fed Chairs: Ben Bernanke and Janet Yellen
出现了两位美联储主席：本·伯南克和珍妮特·耶伦。
How is their independence?
他们的独立性如何呢？
I can only say that
我只能说，
on the surface the government did not interfere too much in their decision-making,
表面上政府并没有过多干预他们的决策，
but their independence
但他们的独立性
is hard to see.
很难体现。
Because during this period,
因为在这一时期，
the Fed's policies
美联储的政策
and the government's needs can be said to be completely matched.
和政府的需求可以说是完全契合的。
In order to cope with the financial crisis,
为了应对金融危机，
the Fed has been implementing low interest rates, flooding
美联储十多年来一直在实施低利率政策，向
the market with money , and
市场注入大量资金，并通过
printing money and buying government bonds
印钞和购买政府债券来刺激经济
for more than ten years.
。
These policies are not only the market's needs,
这些政策不仅符合市场需求，
but also what the government wants to see
也符合政府的意愿。
Both sides’ demands are now in sync
双方的需求如今已趋于一致。
The Fed, as the middleman, is in the middle, so
美联储作为中间人，处于中间位置，因此
it is very easy to do its job.
其运作相对容易。
Therefore, during this period
所以，在此期间，
you rarely hear
你很少听到
the president raise any objections to the Fed.
总统对美联储提出任何异议。
in every congressional hearing.
每次国会听证会上也只有些许紧张气氛。
So in this post-financial crisis era,
因此，在后金融危机时代，
I give the Fed's independence
我对美联储的独立性评分为
a 7.
7分。
You see, we just mentioned that
你看，我们刚才提到，
the Fed and the Treasury have been arguing for so many years
美联储和财政部多年来一直在争论
mainly around monetary policy such as
货币政策，例如
whether to cut interest rates
是否降息。
However, after the financial crisis,
然而，金融危机后，
the Fedhas greatly strengthened one of its rights
美联储极大地加强了其
which is to regulate
监管
banks and financial institutions.
银行和金融机构的权力。
In fact, the Federal Reserve has always had
事实上，美联储一直拥有
this right
这项权力，
but it was not mentioned just now
只是之前没有提及，
because this role was not very prominent before.
因为这项权力以前并不突出。
However, after 2008,
然而，2008年之后，
the United States passed the important "Dodd-Frank Act", which
美国通过了重要的《多德-弗兰克法案》。 这项法案
greatly strengthened
极大地加强了
the regulatory requirements for large financial institutions
对大型金融机构的监管要求，
and a very important executor
而
is the Federal Reserve.
美联储是这项法案的重要执行机构。
Therefore, when people in Wall Street investment banks
因此，华尔街投资银行的人士
hear about this bill, they are overwhelmed.
听到这项法案时都感到震惊。
Various risk indicators, capital adequacy ratios, etc.
各种风险指标、资本充足率等等
are very strict.
都非常严格。
Do you think this is a bit of an overreaction?
你认为这有点反应过度吗？
I think there’s definitely at least a bit of it
我认为肯定有一定程度的过度反应，
but it is
但
actually very difficult to correct the wrongs.
实际上纠正错误非常困难。
After being so strict
在如此严格的监管下，
some small banks such as Silicon Valley Bank went bankrupt.
一些小型银行，例如硅谷银行，都破产了。在2020年之前，
The struggle around the independence of regulatory power
围绕监管权力独立性的斗争
was actually not great
其实并不激烈。
After all, the Fed was printing money on a large scale and
毕竟，美联储当时正在大规模印钞，实施
unprecedented quantitative easing.
前所未有的量化宽松政策。
Everyone made money,
每个人都从中获利，
so no one said anything.
所以没有人提出异议。
But now,
但现在，
interest rates have been increased
利率在
While tightening,
收紧的同时却提高了，
supervision is still so strict, so
监管依然如此严格，因此
resistance has risen.
阻力也随之增大。
Although now
尽管
Trump is clamouring for the Fed to cut interest rates
特朗普现在呼吁美联储降息
actually, you can see from Bessent’s interview that
，但从贝森特的采访中可以看出，
from an institutional perspective,
从制度角度来看，
what they want to cut is not the Federal Reserve’s monetary policy
他们真正想要削减的不是美联储的货币政策，
but their regulatory power.
而是其监管权力。
Well, finally,
好吧，最后……
we have come to this post-pandemic era,
我们已经进入了后疫情时代、
the era of trade wars
贸易战时代
or the Trump era
或特朗普时代。
Powell seems to be more inclined to
鲍威尔似乎更倾向于
implement monetary policy that is more independent.
实施更加独立的货币政策。
It can be tough when it needs to be
必要时，他会采取强硬手段，
but it will compromise a little
但
when it encounters pressure.
遇到压力时也会做出一些妥协。
That is to say,
也就是说，
it will cooperate with the Treasury Department
他会与财政部
and the President
和总统合作。
For example, it began to comply with the demands of the Republican Party
例如，他开始顺应共和党的要求，
and gradually relax the supervision of financial institutions.
逐步放松对金融机构的监管。
During the pandemic
疫情期间，
it also worked with the Treasury Department to provide
他也与财政部合作，向
loans to local governments and small and medium-sized enterprises, etc.
地方政府和中小企业提供贷款等等。
You can't say that the Fed has given in,
你不能说美联储已经屈服，
because it is indeed necessary
因为这确实是必要的，
but the overall feeling is still relatively loose.
但总体感觉仍然相对宽松。
While maintaining independence, it
在保持独立性的同时，他
will also take into account the White House
也会考虑白宫
and the Treasury Department.
和财政部的意见。
So now the independence score is 8 points.
所以现在他的独立性得分是8分。
After more than 100 years,
一百多年过去了，
Do you have a feeling that
你是否感觉，
at the bottom level,
从根本上讲，《
the Federal Reserve Act protects the independence of the Federal Reserve
联邦储备法》保护了美联储的独立性，
but in fact
但实际上
it still requires specific people to play against each other.
仍然需要特定人员相互博弈？
Let's see how Trump plans to play
让我们看看特朗普打算如何与
the White House and the Treasury Department.
白宫和……周旋。 财政部。
What methods does he have to control the Fed
他有哪些方法可以控制美联储
and put pressure on the Fed
并向其施压？
The first move is personnel.
第一步是人事变动。
Can Trump really fire Powell?
特朗普真的能解雇鲍威尔吗？
The simple answer is no,
答案很简单：不能，
unless Trump can cite enough legitimate reasons
除非特朗普能拿出足够多的正当理由，
such as proving that Powell has violated the law
例如证明鲍威尔
seriously neglected his duties,
严重违法、玩忽职守、
morally corrupt,
道德败坏、
mentally ill, etc.
精神失常等等。
It seems that if Trump wants to fire Powell,
看来，如果特朗普想解雇鲍威尔，
he has to use labour arbitration
他只能诉诸劳资仲裁，而
currently seems
目前看来
to have a very low possibility.
可能性极低。
The appointment mechanism for the Fed chairman is as follows:
美联储主席的任命机制如下：
the president of the United States nominates
美国总统提名，
and then the Senate approves the nomination, and the chairman
参议院批准，主席
can be re-elected
可连任
for a four-year
四年。
The president cannot fire the
总统不能仅仅
just because he is dissatisfied
因为
with the Fed's policies.
对美联储的政策不满就解雇现任主席。
So even if Trump wants to replace him
因此，即使特朗普想更换鲍威尔，也
he has to wait until the end of his four-year term
必须等到他四年任期结束
to appoint a new chairman.
才能任命新主席。
Powell was nominated
鲍威尔是
and took office during Trump's first term
在特朗普第一任期内被提名并就职的，
and was later re-elected during Biden's term,
后来在拜登任期内连任，
so his term expires in 2026.
因此他的任期将于2026年到期。
Trump can
特朗普可以 特朗普本可以像尼克松当年任命马丁那样，
announce the next chairman in advance
提前宣布下一任主席，
and use this "shadow chairman" to sideline Powell,
并利用这位“影子主席”来架空鲍威尔，
but he has not done it so far.
但他至今尚未这样做。
But let me tell you,
不过，我要说的是，
if Trump actually wants to influence the Fed,
如果特朗普真的想影响美联储，
he doesn't necessarily have
他未必非得
to target Powell alone,
只针对鲍威尔一人，
because the Fed has a very important feature
因为美联储有一个非常重要的特点：
that is, he is not alone.
他并非孤军奋战。
In fact, all major decisions of the Fed
事实上，美联储的所有重大决策
are
都是
jointly decided by
由
the Federal Open Committee (FOMC), which is composed of 12 people.
联邦公开市场委员会（FOMC）共同决定的，该委员会由12人组成。
The weight of each vote here is the same,
每张选票的权重相同，
so in theory,
因此理论上讲，
the chairman does not have more voting power
主席并没有拥有更大的投票权，
and it does not mean that all of it is up to the chairman.
也并不意味着所有决定都由主席一人做出。
So for Trump,
所以，假设特朗普
assuming that he can control the majority of these 12 people,
能够控制这12人中的大多数，
he can control and influence the Fed's decision-making.
他就能控制并影响美联储的决策。
From a mechanism perspective,
从机制上看，这
7 of the 12 people
12人中有7人
are appointed by the government
由政府任命
and 5 are from local reserve bank presidents.
，5人来自地方储备银行行长。
Those who are interested in
有兴趣了解
how they are rotated and selected
他们如何轮换和选拔的人
can go to watch the video we talked about the Federal Reserve.
可以观看我们之前讨论过的关于美联储的视频。
In short, he has so many people making decisions together
简而言之，他让这么多人共同参与决策。
in order to balance
为了平衡
the relationship between the government, the bank, and the market.
政府、银行和市场之间的关系，美联储设立了联邦公开市场委员会（FOMC）。
But even the 7 people chosen by the government
但即使是政府指定的7人也
cannot be replaced at will.
不能随意更换。
Everyone has an extra-long term of 14 years,
每个人的任期都长达14年，
and one expires every two years
每两年轮换一人。
For example,
例如，
although Powell's term as chairman expires in 2026,
鲍威尔的美联储主席任期虽然在2026年结束，但
his term as a director will not end until 2028.
他的董事任期要到2028年才结束。
So even if he retires next year,
因此，即使他明年退休，
he will most likely still be a director
他很可能仍然是
in this team of 12 people,
这12人团队中的董事，
and he will still have voting rights.
并且仍然拥有投票权。
In fact, the way the government
事实上，除了任命主席之外，政府
has always tried to influence the Fed
一直以来试图影响美联储的一种方式
is to stuff more doves into the FOMC.
就是在FOMC中安插更多鸽派人士。
Doves are those who advocate monetary easing.
鸽派人士主张宽松货币政策。
Generally, when people analyse the monetary policy of the Fed,
通常，人们在分析美联储的货币政策时，
they will analyse these 12 people. Who is a hawk
会分析这12人，谁是鹰派
and who is a dove
，谁是鸽派，
what each person's inclination is.
每个人的倾向都非常明显。
We can see that
我们可以看到，
most of the seven people chosen by the government tend to be dovish
政府指定的7人中，大多数人倾向于鸽派，而
The hawks basically come from the reserve bank.
鹰派人士则主要来自储备银行。
The White House is continuously
白宫一直在
influencing the Fed's decision-making indirectly through personnel appointments
通过人事任命间接影响美联储的决策。
But at this point in time,
但目前
it is impossible for him to replace all seven people at once,
他不可能一次性更换全部七名美联储主席，
so it is still difficult to achieve immediate results.
因此短期内难以见效。特朗普干预美联储的
Another possible way
另一种可能方式
is through executive orders.
是通过行政命令。
Although it is difficult to change legislation
虽然修改立法困难重重，但
the president can use executive orders
总统可以利用行政命令
to temporarily restrict the Fed.
暂时限制美联储的权力。
For example, in February of this year,
例如，今年2月，
Trump issued an executive order No. 14215 requiring all independent agencies
特朗普发布了第14215号行政命令，要求所有独立机构在发布重大法规前必须将
to submit major regulations to the White House for review
重大法规提交白宫审查，
and you must communicate with the White House regularly
并定期与白宫沟通。
You see, this is actually what we mentioned before.
你看，这其实就是我们之前提到的。
Trump and Bessent
特朗普和贝森特
want to limit the Fed's regulatory power
想要限制美联储的监管权力，
and want it to relax regulation.
并希望它放松监管。
In fact, in addition to these two tricks, the most common way for
事实上，除了这两种手段之外，特朗普影响美联储最常见的方式
is through public opinion
是通过舆论引导，
saying that Europe has cut interest rates,
比如“欧洲都降息了，
why haven't you cut them yet?
为什么你们还没降息？
If the US economy continues like this, it will be over.
如果美国经济继续这样下去，就完了。
Powell, you are always too late,
鲍威尔，你总是太迟了，
always wrong, always Too Late
总是错的，总是太迟了。”
in short, he wants to use these to influence public opinion
总之，他想利用这些手段…… 影响公众舆论
and put pressure on the Federal Reserve.
并向美联储施压。
However, it seems that
然而，
the effect of this move is not very obvious
此举的效果似乎并不明显，甚至
and it is even a bit counterproductive.
有些适得其反。
In fact, although Trump is the president of the United States,
事实上，尽管特朗普是美国总统，但
it can be said that there are few people on the earth who have more power than him
可以说世界上很少有人比他更有权力。
But one of the institutions that left him feeling most helpless
然而，令他感到最无助
and at a loss was the Federal Reserve.
和不知所措的机构之一就是美联储。
You can see that he can directly throw various heavy policies
他可以直接
at other departments, organizations, and even countries
对其他部门、机构甚至国家施加各种强硬政策，他对美联储的批评
He was harsher than anyone
比任何人都严厉，
yet when it came to actual, tangible action
但当涉及到实际行动时，
he made no move at all.
他却毫无作为。
He just couldn't help but threaten to fire Powell,
他只是威胁要解雇鲍威尔，
but he gave in within a week.
但一周之内就屈服了。
For example, the executive order
例如，这项行政命令要求
everything must be reported to the White House.
所有事项都必须向白宫汇报。
Although the power of the Fed has been weakened
尽管美联储的权力已被削弱，但
it only dares to focus on supervision
它只敢专注于监督，
because the executive order
因为该行政命令
specifically adds a clause
特意增加了一条条款，将
that does not include the monetary policy of the Fed
美联储的货币政策排除在外。
That is, the monetary policy of the Fed
也就是说，美联储的货币政策
does not need to be reviewed by the White House.
不需要白宫审查。
Why?
为什么？因为
There is no need for it to add this clause.
没有必要添加这条条款。
This actually indirectly confirms a logic
这实际上 这间接证实了
that the White House dare not.
白宫不敢这么做的逻辑。
Although it wants to
尽管白宫想干预
in the policy of the Federal Reserve.
美联储的政策，但它不敢过度干预。
Even if it wants to try
即使想尝试，
it is extremely cautious
它也极其谨慎，
because the Federal Reserve
因为美联储
is not simply an independent institution.
并非一个独立的机构，背后有强大的力量支撑。
What has a deterrent effect on the US government
真正对美国政府起到威慑作用的
is the trust of the market.
是市场的信任。
You can see that from 1951 to the present,
你可以看到，从1951年至今，
Martin, Walker, Greenspan,
马丁、沃克、格林斯潘、
Bernanke, Yellen, and Powell
伯南克、耶伦和鲍威尔一步步
have built up
建立起了
this sustainable market trust
这种可持续的市场信任。
because of this trust
正是因为这种信任，
the US dollar become an international reserve currency
美元才成为国际储备货币，
allows global capital and global central banks
使得全球资本和各国央行能够放心地
to invest in the US dollar
投资美元
without too many concerns.
。
I dare say that this trust
我敢说，这种信任
far exceeds the market's trust in the US government.
远远超过了市场对美国政府的信任。
You see, tariffs
你看，关税
sound very important.
听起来非常重要，
They connect so many countries.
它牵涉到很多国家。
We also analysed it in the last issue.
我们在上一期也分析过。
The actual GDP of imports is only 3 trillion US dollars.
进口的实际GDP只有3万亿美元，
The scope is wide, but the degree of connection is not so close
范围很广，但关联程度却没那么紧密。
The financial market is different.
金融市场则不同，
You can say that
可以说它
it is deeply connected to the bone marrow of the United States
与美国的骨髓紧密相连。 无论
Whether it is government bonds,
是政府债券、
bonds of all large companies, or
所有大公司的债券，还是
stocks of all large companies,
所有大公司的股票，
they are all based on
它们都建立在
the global market's trust in the US financial market
全球市场对美国金融市场
and the US dollar
和美元的信任之上。而
The main pillar behind this
支撑这一切的主要支柱
is the Federal Reserve.
是美联储。
So it is one thing for Trump to force him to cut interest rates,
因此，特朗普迫使美联储降息是一回事，
but if they accidentally undermine the foundation of the dollar
但如果他们不小心动摇了美元的根基，
things could go really bad.
情况可能会变得非常糟糕。
Bessent has repeatedly warned the White House that
贝森特曾多次警告白宫，
firing Powell may cause market turmoil
解雇鲍威尔可能会引发市场动荡。
However, Trump's recent series of actions
然而，特朗普近期的一系列举动
have indeed shaken the market's trust
确实动摇了市场
in the dollar.
对美元的信心。
Other countries
其他国家
are more or less de-dollarizing
或多或少都
to a certain extent.
在一定程度上去美元化。
Although the market generally believes that
尽管市场普遍认为
Trump dare not touch the Federal Reserve
特朗普不敢触碰美联储，
and he dare not weaken the independence of the Federal Reserve
也不敢削弱美联储的独立性，
but they are still worried
但他们仍然担心，
that if he is in a bad mood one day, he will
如果他哪天心情不好，可能会
come up with a policy.
出台一项政策。
If this really happens,
如果这种情况真的发生，
it will be a real black swan event
那将是市场的一次真正的黑天鹅事件
for the market .
。
Mr. President,
总统先生，
I want you to know that
我想让您知道，
I have lowered the discount rate
我降低贴现率是
to help you become president.
为了帮助您当选总统。
It ushered in
这引出了保罗·沃克的
the highlight moment
高光时刻。
It is called the Walker miracle .
它被称为沃克奇迹。是
I added it myself.
我自己添加的。